PS

Pankaj Khandelwal

(ACS, M.Com. & LLB.)

To,

The Manager, HR

Respected Sir/ Madam,

Warm Greetings to you.

I am writing to apply for the position of "Company Secretary" with your organization having experience of more than 3 years. I would like to introduce myself in Brief, I am Associate Member of the Institute of Company Secretary of India (ICSI) and LLB. from University of Raiasthan.

I am seeking to align myself to gain extensive experience of working with talented team, meeting targets and delivering desired solutions. As per my experience, I have practical knowledge in Secretarial and Legal department of a professionally managed organization.

I am an energetic, self-motivated person and learning new things is my passion. I can stretch my working hours as per the need of the origination or work pressure. My professional goal is to continue learning and developing my expertise, in the fertile field of corporate law and corporate compliance with an organization of repute and thus, enhancing my knowledge and expertise in the relevant field.

With this goal in mind to enhance my spectrum of knowledge, I hereby attach my **Curriculum Vitae** for your kind perusal.

Looking forward for your positive response.

Thanks & Regards,

Pankaj Khandelwal

E- mail: pankajkhandelwal.2102@gmail.com, M. No.: 8104651686

Enclosed: Curriculum Vitae

CURRICULUM VITAE



PANKAJ KHANDELWAL

ACS-51856

CB-309, Naraina Vihar, Ring Road, New Delhi-110028

Mob: +91 - 8104651686, Email: pankajkhandelwal.2102@gmail.com

CARRER OBJECTIVE

Striving to develop professional and personal skills by working in a dynamic and challenging environment that provides exposure to the globalised commercial world, while adding value to the organisation and thereby economy, through knowledge, effective communication and hard work.

PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATION:

- Completed CS Professional in December 2016 from Institute of Company Secretaries of India (ICSI).
- Completed **Bachelor of Law (LLB.)** from University of Rajasthan in the year 2017.

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION:

DEGREE/EXAM	BOARD/UNIVERSITY	YEAR
M.Com.	University of Rajasthan	2013
B.Com.	University of Rajasthan	2011

WORK EXPERIENCE

• <u>CA - TARUN JAGGI & ASSOCIATES</u> (Since Sep 2017 to Present)

Working as an <u>Practicing Company Secretary</u> and <u>Corporate Compliance Manager</u> in a practicing Chartered Accountant firm established in 1995 at New Delhi, The said firm deals in big four like - DELOTTE, PWC, KPMG and E&Y and overseas as well domestic clients and serving the corporate world in the field with Taxation, Audits, Consultancy, Secretarial, Legal and FEMA.

• <u>CS - DEEPAK ARORA & ASSOCIATES</u> (Jan. 2017 to August 2017)

Worked as a Company Secretary with **M/s Deepak Arora & Associates**, a well reputed Practicing Company Secretaries Firm in Jaipur, Rajasthan established in 1999, from Jan 2017 to August 2017 (8 Months).

CS - DEEPAK ARORA & ASSOCIATES (Sep 2015 to Dec 2016)

Worked as a Management Trainee with **M/s Deepak Arora & Associates**, a well reputed Practicing Company Secretaries Firm in Jaipur, Rajasthan established in 1999, from Sep 2015 to Dec 2016 (15 Months).

BRIEF SYNOPSIS OF EXPERIENCE

Brief description of my <u>post qualification experience</u> is mentioned below:

I. Secretarial Functions:

- ✓ Preparation of Annual Return, Board Reports and other documents related to annual filing.
- ✓ Filing of Annual Return and Financial Statements of Companies in regular and XBRL Mode.
- ✓ Having experience of conducting search & preparing a search report of the Company, required by various banks and corporate from time to time & A Due Diligence Report.
- ✓ Prepared petition related to delay in charge creation before regional director.
- ✓ Drafting of documents including Resolutions, Minutes, Notice and Agreements.
- ✓ Conducted the board meetings via Circulation by Resolution.
- ✓ Drafting of various replies such as notices to companies from the ROC regarding any clarification of non-compliances by companies.
- ✓ Preparation of Minutes of various meetings as per the secretarial standards issued by ICSI.
- ✓ Preparation and filing of papers & Forms for Alteration of Memorandum and Articles of Association u/s 13 and 14 of Companies Act, 2013:
 - Change in Main objects of the Company;
 - Alteration in Authorized Share Capital of the Company;
 - Shifting of Registered Office of the Company one state to another as well as within the local limits of city/town etc.;
 - Adoption of new set of Memorandum and Articles of Association as per Companies Act, 2013.

- ✓ Maintenance of various Statutory Registers i.e. Register of Members, Register of Debenture holders, Register of Directors and Key Managerial Personnel.
- ✓ Secretarial compliances for increasing Share Capital and Allotment, Change of Name/Registered office of the Company.
- ✓ Documentation and filing of e-forms related to appointment, resignation and removal of Directors, Key Managerial Personnel and Auditor of a Company.
- ✓ Preparation of Secretarial Audit Reports, Annual Compliance Reports and Certificate in form MGT-8.
- ✓ Filing of various forms under Companies Act, 2013 & LLP Act, 2008 with ROC.
- ✓ Strike –off of Companies under Section 560 of the Companies Act, 1956 and Section 248 of Companies Act, 2013;
- ✓ Managing procedural formalities pertaining to Allotment of shares and Issue of Shares on Right Basis and Private Placement and issuance of Share Certificates, duplicate share certificate
- ✓ Maintenance of Statutory records like Minutes, Registers, Share Certificates, Transfer deeds, etc.;
- ✓ Managing procedural formalities pertaining to incorporation of Company, LLP, Producer Company, section-8 Company.
- ✓ Assisted in handling and attended the various meeting of the Company such as board meetings, annual general meeting etc.
- ✓ Secretarial Compliances with ROC and other governing bodies and Physical search etc.
- ✓ Financial statements and Annual Return of the Company filed as per the Condonation of Delay Scheme 2018- [CODS-2018] Launched by MCA.
- ✓ Dealt with recent amendments of Companies Act, 2013 like Filing of E-Form DPT-3, MSME -1, Beneficial Significant Owners in form E- Form BEN-2, KYC of Registered office in form INC-22A Active and Director in form DIR-3 KYC.
- ✓ E- Stamping of shares Certificates of Company through SHCIL Portal.
- ✓ Assisted in handing the clients mainly incorporation related and redressal of their quires.
- ✓ Annual filing of LLP forms like LLP Form-11 and Form-8.
- ✓ Stamping of Shares Certificates with the Revenue Department;
- ✓ Prepared check list of various compliances under Companies Act, 2013
- ✓ Liasoning and Interact with various departments and authorities, such as, ROC, RD, MCA, RBI, Official Liquidator and various benches of NCLT

II. <u>Legal and Functions</u>

✓ Drafting, filing the application/petition before National Company Law Tribunal (NCLT) for not holding Annual General Meeting for the Financial Year 2015-16, under Companies Act, 2013.

- ✓ Drafting of other legal documents like Power of Attorney, affidavits and Indemnity Bond etc.
- ✓ Drafting and filing the application/petition before National Company Law Tribunal (NCLT) for not laying the financial statement in Annual General Meeting for the Financial Year 2015-16 under Companies Act, 2013.
- ✓ Appeared before National Company Law Tribunal (NCLT) in the matter of Compounding of offence under Section 441 of Companies Act, 2013
- ✓ Drafting and filing the application/petition before National Company Law Tribunal (NCLT) for not laying the financial statement in Annual General Meeting for the Financial Year 2015-16 under Companies Act, 2013.
- ✓ Drafting of petition and Appeared before Delhi, Mumbai and Chandigarh, NCLT Benches in the matter of Voluntary Liquidation of the Company under Section 59 of Insolvency and Bankruptcy Code, 2016.
- ✓ Worked as an authorised representative of Interim Resolution Professional appointed by NCLT, Delhi Bench.
- ✓ Filing of various forms, OC/FC Claims and status reports with IBBI and NCLT and conducted meeting of Committee of Creditors under Insolvency and Bankruptcy Code, 2016.
- ✓ Filing of Monthly, Quarterly and Half yearly Reports with Indian Institute of Insolvency Professional of ICAI for Voluntary Liquidation of the Companies.

III. Business Registrations and Taxation

- ✓ GST Registration
- ✓ Udhyam Registration at new portal
- ✓ Startup India Registration
- ✓ Income Tax Returns (ITR)
- ✓ Trademark registration
- ✓ Export Incentives under SEIS Schemes

IV. Foreign Investment Related work (FEMA):

- ✓ Allotment of shares to Non-Resident Indian.
- ✓ Registration as an Entity User for Filing of Entity Master Form at FIRMS Portal.
- ✓ E-filing of Advance Reporting Form under old regime.
- ✓ E-filing of FC-GPR Part A and filing (Formerly known as FC-GPR Part B).
- ✓ Handled various queries from RBI as well as Authorized Dealer Banks.
- ✓ Transfer of shares from between Foreign National to Foreign National.
- ✓ Filling of Annual Return on Foreign Liabilities and Assets Reporting by Indian Companies under new online portal.
- ✓ Closure of Liaison office.
- ✓ Annual Filing of Foreign Companies.

V. Other Services:

- ✓ Allotment of DIN and DSC to resident as well as foreign national.
- ✓ Work related to all kinds of Digital Signature Certificates such as Class 2, Class 3 and DGFT.
- ✓ Acquiring of PAN of Companies and LLPs.
- ✓ Acquiring of TAN of Companies.

INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY SKILLS:

- Conversant in MS Office, MS Excel windows.
- Well versed with newly updated MCA portal.
- Conversant with Business Intelligence Tools like SAG-Company Law Software and XBRL Tools. SAG Infotech Taxation Tool.
- Familiar with internet operation (Research, Mail, Site Usage) & all basic functions relating to computer.

KEY SKILLS

- Result Oriented and Resourceful Approach
- Energetic & Self-Confident with 'will-do' mindset.
- Smart Working and Positive Attitude
- Self-Motivator

PERSONAL DOSSIER

Father's Name : Mr. H. M. Khandelwal

Linguistic Proficiency: English & Hindi

Date of Birth: February 21, 1992

Gender : Male

Nationality : Indian

Current CTC: 4.8 Lakhs

Marital Status : Married

Notice Period : 30 days

Hobbies : Reading Case Laws and Listening Music

Declaration:	
, Pankaj Khandelwal, do hereby affirm an s true to the best of my Knowledge and be	d declare that the information furnished above elief.
Place: New Delhi	Sd/-
	CS PANKAJ KHANDELWAL